Jeremy Clough

I am a degree educated Engineer with a background in providing advanced software technical support to Enterprise customers. I have experience of investigating complex software issues to code level in both UNIX/Linux and Windows environments. With a background that has included working as a Release Engineer, a Software Developer and a Support Engineer, I have experience of the full software lifecycle and how to communicate software issues to Project Managers, Engineering teams, Support teams and customers. With an attention to detail and a focus on doing things the right way, I enjoy utilizing my software coding skills and experience to get to the root of a problem.

Qualifications

1992 – 1996 Master of Engineering (MEng) 2:1 Hons

Mechanical Engineering with German

University of Birmingham, Edgbaston, B15 2TT

1990 - 1992 **A-Level**

Little Heath Secondary School, Tilehurst, Reading, Berks Pure Maths (A), Applied Maths (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (C)

Employment history

Veritas, Reading, RG2 6UH

Advanced Support Engineer for Veritas eDiscovery Platform

March 2012 - today

My primary day-to-day duties involve providing support to Enterprise customers using the Veritas Clearwell eDiscovery software product. Veritas Clearwell supports the full EDRM eDiscovery workflow and is based around a Tomcat webserver running on a Windows Server. Various plugin software components, written in a variety of software languages, provide the ability to collect file and email data from numerous different sources. My work involves investigating product issues to code-level (primarily C/C++ and Java), debugging using windbg and Eclipse and reproducing issues for escalation to our Engineering team. This upfront analysis work is also used for the creation of technical knowledgebase articles for internal and customer use, and for constructing software patches that can give the Engineering team a starting-off point for the issue.

Barracuda Networks, Basingstoke, RG22 6HY

Barracuda Networks manufactures and provides 24/7 support for network appliances based on the Linux OS and Open Source technologies including Apache, MySQL, Postfix, and Perl.

Technical Support Engineer

Feb 2010 - Feb 2012

My duties involved providing telephone and email support to EMEA customers. Remotely accessing the command-line and web UI of customer devices, I would troubleshoot product software and hardware issues. For new issues, I would log bug reports with reproduction steps, and, whenever possible, I would investigate issues to the source code level (mainly Perl) and produce software fixes or workarounds for the customer. The products I supported were the Barracuda Email anti-Spam device and the data Backup solution with additional cloud-based storage.

Micro Focus Ltd, Newbury, RG14 1QN

The major Micro Focus product is a COBOL software development environment for Windows and

UNIX/Linux platforms. The product enables companies to migrate their legacy COBOL-based software systems to modern platforms and extend them with technologies such as Web Services, J2EE, .Net and XML

Software Developer

January 2009 - Aug 2009

Following agile software development practices, my duties as part of the Micro Focus 'Core' development team involved investigating and resolving problems with the COBOL debug engine and COBOL runtime system. Both of these were written in C code. My other duties included implementing new product features and writing accompanying tests.

Senior Software Release Engineer

April 2003 - December 2008

As a senior member of the Release Engineering team, I was responsible for producing the software builds and Fix-packs for the Micro Focus Server Express product. Platforms supported included IBM AIX, Compaq Tru64, HP-UX (PA-RISC, Itanium), Red Hat (x86-64, PPC, 390), Solaris (Intel, Sparc), SuSE (x86-64, PPC, 390) and SCO UnixWare. My role involved working very closely with Project Management, Development, Testing and Support teams. My duties included integrating new software components into the build system, producing initial ports of the product to new UNIX and Linux platforms, investigating build, runtime and test system issues, and maintaining the product installation and Fix-pack systems.

Compaq Computer Ltd, Reading, RG2 OTE

Systems Development/Integration Engineer, UK Telecommunications Integration Service (TIS) practice.

June 1999 - Aug 2002

My main duties involved producing and maintaining software components for Telecoms companies including Vodafone, BT, Alcatel and Cable & Wireless. These software components were created for the Compaq TeMIP© Network Management software framework. My other duties included investigating legacy software issues and implementing and documenting new functionality.

Kerridge Computer Company Ltd, Newbury, RG14 1HT

Kerridge Computer Company were an independent software house, providing software solutions for Distribution, Wholesale and Merchant industries.

UNIX Software Engineer

Sept 1996 - Sept 1997

My duties involved programming in C on UNIX using the Lex and Yacc tools, to extend the features of the in-house interpreted programming language called KCML (Kerridge C Macro Language).

Hobbies

Reading FC, Holidaying in France, Playing the Guitar.